Register of the Marshall Green papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1948-1998
  - "Closing the Gap between Expectations and Realities," address, Commencement Day, Graduate School of Business, New Hampshire College, Manchester, New Hampshire, 1985 August (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - "What You Always Wanted to Know About Foreign Affairs But Were Afraid to Have Any," address, benefit dinner, World Affairs Council of Maine, Portland, Maine, 1985 August 8 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - "East Asia in Geopolitical Perspective: An American View," address, opening of Business International Chief Executive Officers' Roundtable, Biltmore Hotel, Phoenix, Arizona, 1986 January 15 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - "The Marshall Plan: A Humorous Account of Some Checkered Doings by the Striped-Pants Set," Foreign Service Journal, 1986 February (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - "Some Reflections on U.S.-East Asian Strategic Relations: Past, Present and Future," excerpts, banquet address, East Asian Symposium, National Defense University, Fort Lesley J. McNair, Washington, D.C., 1986 February 13 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Interview concerning Indonesia, 1965-1969, Robert J. Martens, Foreign Service History Center, Washington, D.C., 1987 May 12 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Lecture, Diplomatic Lecture Series of 1987-1988, Hiltops, Hartwick College, Oneonta, New York, 1987 November 19 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Review of Dennis Phillips, Ambivalent Allies: Myth and Reality in the Australian-American Relationship, Journal of International Law and Politics, 1988 Fall (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - "Evolution of U.S.-China Policy 1956-1973: Memoirs of an Insider,", 1989 February?
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 7: 25)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 7: 26)
    - Reviews, 1989 March 2-4 (Box-folder 7: 27)
  - "Working with Dulles: An Insider's Account of the Taiwan Straits Crisis," Foreign Service Journal, 1989 May (Box-folder 7: 28)
    See also: Box 4, Folders 11-13.
    Printed copy. Includes a letter from W. D. Howells, 1988 July 26.
  - Statement, Subcommittee on International Operations, Committee on Foreign Affairs, United States House of Representatives, 1989 September 21 (Box-folder 7: 29)
  - "Issues of the 1990's: Views from the Pacific Rim and Washington," remarks, XXth Annual Leadership Conference, Center for the Study of the Presidency, Los Angeles, California, 1989 October 27 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - "The West Rim of the Pacific: Looking Ahead," Diplomatic and Consular Officers Retired (DACOR) luncheon address, Washington, D.C.?, 1990 July 13 (Box-folder 7: 31)
  - "Vietnam and the Persian Gulf Wars," address, Public Members Association, Foreign Service, F Street Club, Washington, D.C., 1991 May 2
    - Background materials (Box-folder 7: 32)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 8: 1)
      Includes typescript excerpts from a slightly different version with a different title and holograph notes.
  - Review of Indonesia: Crisis and Transformation, 1965-1968, James Murray and David Jenkins, Sydney Morning Herald, 1991 August 16 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - "The Paris Peace Talks on Vietnam," address, Institute of Conflict Analysis and Resolution (ICAR), George Mason University, Virginia, 1993 May 7 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - War and Peace with China, 1994
    - Background materials (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Holograph notes (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - "Christian Ethics and Public Life," remarks, Palm Sunday, St. David's Church, 1998 (Box-folder 8: 8)
- Office File, 1932-1998
  Clippings and printed matter, letters, lists, memoranda, minutes of meetings, schedule, speech transcripts, and telegrams relating to Green's positions at the Department of State, arranged in two groups, countries and regions, and population affairs, thereunder alphabetically by country or subject.
  - Countries and regions
    See also: Speeches and Writings and Travel File.
    Includes clippings and printed matter, correspondence, memoranda, notes, and speeches.
    - Asia, 1958-1998 (Box-folder 8: 9-13)
      Includes materials relating to conversation with Richard Nixon, 1969-1972, and regional cooperation.
      - East Asia
        - 1960 (Box-folder 8: 14)
        - 1969-1984 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
      - Far Eastern Asia, 1957-1998 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - Southeast Asia, 1981-1997 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Australia
      - Undated (Box-folder 9: 5)
      - Clippings and printed matter, 1967-1988 (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - Consultation and leave records, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 9: 8-9)
      - Letters, 1973-1974
        - Appointment and resignation, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 9: 10)
        - Letters from Australians in response to Senator Bill Brown's attack on Marshall Green, 1974 June-July (Box-folder 9: 11-12)
      - List of files, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 9: 13)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9: 14-15)
      - Schedule, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 16)
      - Speeches and writings
        Includes related material.
        - General
          - List of speeches, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 10: 1)
          - Notes, 1973-1997 (Box-folder 10: 2)
        - Undated (Box-folder 10: 3-4)
        - 1971 May – 1973 December 5 (Box-folder 10: 5-20)
        - 1974 March 11 – 1975 June 3 (Box-folder 11: 1-20)
        - 1975 June 10 – 1988 February (Box-folder 12: 1-7)
      - Subject file
        - Australia - bicentennial, 1975-1985 (Box-folder 12: 8)
        - Australia-New Zealand, 1973-1995 (Box-folder 12: 9-10)
          See also: Box 19, Folder 11.
        - Australia - political/economic, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 12: 11)
        - Australia revisited, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
        - Friends in Australia, 1975 (Box-folder 13: 3)
      - Telegrams, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 13: 4)
      - Miscellany, 1973-1997 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Cambodia
      - General, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 13: 6-7)
      - Clippings and printed matter, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - China
      - General
        - Undated (Box-folder 13: 9-10)
        - 1932-1998 (Box-folder 14: 1-9)
      - Clippings and printed matter
        - 1965-1972 (Box-folder 14: 10-11)
        - 1973-1998 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
      - Subject file
        - Conversation with Jack Service regarding his visit to China, 1971 (Box-folder 15: 3)
          Includes an article by him, undated.
        - President Nixon's trip to China, 1972 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Egypt, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Hong Kong, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 15: 6-7)
    - Indonesia
      - General
        - General
          - Indonesia revisited, 1988 (Box-folder 15: 8)
          - "Scholars papers,", 1969-1985 (Box-folder 15: 9)
        - Undated (Box-folder 15: 10-11)
        - 1958-1964 (Box-folder 15: 12)
        - 1965-1995 (Box-folder 16: 1-9)
        - 1996-1998 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
      - Clippings and printed matter, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Japan
      - General
        - General
          - Undated (Box-folder 17: 4)
          - 1933-1974 (Box-folder 17: 5-10)
          - 1979-1998 (Box-folder 18: 1-3)
        - Clippings and printed matter, 1972-1998 (Box-folder 18: 4)
        - Interviews, 1971-1998 (Box-folder 18: 5)
      - Subject file
        - The Japan-America Society
          - General
            - Undated (Box-folder 18: 6)
            - 1947-1998 (Box-folder 18: 7-12)
          - Educational Fund, 1983-1998 (Box-folder 18: 13)
        - Japan - National Archive Study Project, 1960-1996 (Box-folder 19: 1)
        - Japan - researcher – Robert Eldridge, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Korea, 1948-1998 (Box-folder 19: 3-11)
    - Laos, 1949-1989 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - New Zealand, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 19: 13)
      See also: Box 12, Folders 9-10.
    - Philippines, 1972-1994 (Box-folder 19: 14)
    - Republic of Nauru, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Soviet Union, 1971-1987 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - Vietnam
      - General, 1963-1995 (Box-folder 20: 3-6)
      - Subject file
        - Vietnam settlement, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 20: 7-8)
          See also: Correspondence/Henry Kissinger in Box 2, Folder 14.
        - Nixon Doctrine, 1969 (Box-folder 20: 9)
        - Ellsberg trial, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Population affairs
    See also: Travel File/Travel reports, Boxes 29-30.
    - Immigration, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 21: 1-8)
    - Population
      - General
        - Undated (Box-folder 22: 1-2)
        - 1966-1992 (Box-folder 22: 3-10)
        - 1993-1998 (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
      - Articles for Population and Development Review (PDF), 1993 (Box-folder 23: 3)
      - Speeches and writings
        - Undated (Box-folder 23: 4)
        - 1965–1977 (Box-folder 23: 5-10)
        - 1978-1986 (Box-folder 24: 1-10)
        - 1987-1997 (Box-folder 25: 1-8)
      - Subject file
        - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) project, 1991 (Box-folder 25: 9-10)
        - Population Crisis Committee
          - 1984-1993 (Box-folder 25: 11-13)
          - 1994-1995 (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Refugees
      - Undated (Box-folder 26: 2)
      - 1978-1982 (Box-folder 26: 3-8)
      - 1984-1991 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Miscellany, 1971-1998 (Box-folder 27: 2)
- Travel File, 1969-1997
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, reports, and schedules, arranged in two groups, trip files and trip reports, thereunder chronologically.
  - Trip files
    - Shanghai (post trip), 1972 February 29 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - 1973
      - United States, July 24 (Box-folder 27: 4)
      - Brisbane, Australia, September 5-8 (Box-folder 27: 5)
      - Adelaide, Australia, September 18-19 (Box-folder 27: 6)
      - Perth, Australia, September 19-21 (Box-folder 27: 7)
      - Northwest Cape, Australia, September 22-24 (Box-folder 27: 8)
      - Robe River, Australia, September 24-25 (Box-folder 27: 9)
      - Alice Springs, Australia, September 25-27 (Box-folder 27: 10)
      - Melbourne, Australia, October 29-30 (Box-folder 27: 11)
    - Melbourne, Australia, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 27: 12)
    - 1974
      - Newcastle and Maitland, Australia, April 9-10 (Box-folder 27: 13)
      - Freeport Minerals' visit to Townsville, Australia, and Irian Jaya, Indonesia, April 29–May 4 (Box-folder 27: 14)
      - Adelaide, Australia, May 27-28 (Box-folder 27: 15)
      - Coleraine, Victoria and Nareen Fraser's property, Australia, May 29 (Box-folder 27: 16)
      - Dubbo, New South Wales, Australia, November 20 (Box-folder 28: 1)
      - West Wyalong, New South Wales, Australia, November 25 (Box-folder 28: 2)
      - Antarctica, December 21-30 (Box-folder 28: 3)
    - Sydney, Australia, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 28: 4)
    - 1975
      - Bowral, New South Wales, Australia, January 21 (Box-folder 28: 5)
      - New York, Chicago, and San Francisco, March 11-13 (Box-folder 28: 6)
      - Western Australia, May 14-20 (Box-folder 28: 7)
      - Brazil, Colombia, and the Dominican Republic, July 12-22 (Box-folder 28: 8)
    - Asia, 1982 (Box-folder 28: 9)
    - Hong Kong, 1993 (Box-folder 28: 10)
    - China, 1997 March 1-5 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Trip reports
    See also: Population affairs, Boxes 21-27.
    - "Indonesia and Australasia Revisited,", undated (Box-folder 29: 1)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 29: 2)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 29: 3)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 29: 4-5)
    - 1977-1980 (Box-folder 29: 6-7)
    - 1981-1982 (Box-folder 29: 8-9)
    - 1983-1985 June (Box-folder 29: 10)
    - 1985 November – 1988 March 7 (Box-folder 30: 1-2)
- Subject File, 1898-1995
  Brochure, clippings and printed matter, correspondence, interviews, list, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletters, notes, proposal, remarks, and reports, arranged by name of organization or subject.
  - Air pollution - Asia, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - American Academy of Diplomacy
    - Undated (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 30: 5)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - 1985-1988 (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - 1989-1997 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Association for Diplomatic Studies, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 31: 1-4)
  - Gaiko Forum, 1994 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Institute for Development Training, 1990 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Institute for Strategic Studies, 1971 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - The Other Club, 1898-1994 (Box-folder 31: 8)
- Computer Disk, 1991 (Reading room Workstation)
  Organizing statements for the Truman Awards Program, designed for leaders of international cooperation and development. One 5.25-inch floppy disk in 31: 9.
- Photographs, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 31: 10)
  1 print depicting Marshall Green sitting in a room and 1 print depicting Green along with Bruce Johnston and Bill Schulz inspecting the model of a generating plant during his visit to the Latrobe Valley in the State of Victoria, Australia, undated.
  4 prints depicting unidentified individuals, undated.
  4 prints depicting Marshall Green with President Sukarno and 1 print depicting a group of unidentified people gathered in an open area, undated.
  1 print depicting Green with an unidentified individual, 1983 January.
  1 print depicting Green accompanied by Paul Wolfowitz shaking hands with President Suharto, 1988 February 10.
  2 prints depicting Green and members of the Other Club, Holyoke, Massachusetts, 1992 October 1.
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1958-1987
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled, unclassified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2010 release of records, circa 1959-1981; 5.0 digital files (Reading room Workstation)
    The records relate to Laos, Taiwan, Queensland, and population matters in Egypt and Pakistan.
  - 2011 September release of records, 1981 July (Box-folder 31: 11)
    Unclassified incoming telegrams relating to foreign press coverage of visit by Special Refugee Advisory Panel to Southeast Asia.
  - 2013 release of records, 1958-1987; 36.0 digital files (Reading room Workstation)
    Most of the records relate to the Special Refugee Advisory Panel (SRAP), Laos, and Indonesia. Other topics include Korea and the negotiating volumes in the trial of Ellsberg and Russo.
  - 2015 May release of records, 1987 (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - 2015 July release of records, 1958 (Box-folder 31: 13)
    Memorandum from Walter S. Robertson (Assistant Secretary of State for Far Eastern Affairs) to the Secretary of State (John Foster Dulles), subject "Recommended Action to Meet the Taiwan Straits Issue."
    More legible version of this memorandum can be found on the State Department's website: https://history.state.gov/historicaldocuments/frus1958-60v19/d38 (accessed 28 July 2015).